(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T22:11:51.289931",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
プロデューサー！！！
Producer!!!
どうしたんですか、ラプラスさん
What's the matter, Laplus-san?
次の生誕ライブ、なんにもやることないんですけど！！
I have absolutely nothing to do for my next birthday live stream!!
毎年いろいろやってきたけど…
I've done various things every year, but...
去年は、ミームやりすぎて、ミームキャラになっちゃったし、
last year, I did too many memes and ended up as a meme character...
どうしよう！
What should I do?!
デビュー当時のアイドルらしさはもう見る影もないですからね
There's really no trace left of your idol-like image from your debut days, is there?
吾輩はどうやっていけば良いんだー
What should I do for my solo live concert?!
勝手にTire表とか作っちゃいましたし...
We already made that tier list without permission...
それだ！
That's it!
ほら、吾輩おねえさん大好きでしょ？
You see, I absolutely love older sisters!
？？？？
????
ホロライブのお姉さん大集合させよう！
Let's gather all the older sisters of Hololive!
お姉さんライブだ！！！
An "Older Sister Live"!
‥‥
....
大丈夫だよ！当てはある！！！吾輩に任せとけ！
It's fine! I have someone in mind! Leave it to me!
それはちゃんとラプラスさんのライブとして成立するんですか？
But will that really work as a concert for you, Laplus-san?
そこは...なんかいい感じにやるんだよ！
We'll... figure something out and make it work!
ていうか、吾輩のこと好きなファンならさ、やっぱり吾輩が好きなことしてるところ、楽しく見てくれるんじゃない！？
Besides, my fans would love to see me doing what I enjoy, right?
限度があるんじゃないですか？
Don't you think there's a limit to that?
とにかくやるって決めたらやるの！いくぞーー！！！
Anyway, once I decide to do something, I do it! Let's go!!!
ノエルさん！
Noel-san!
どうしたの？ラプちゃん？
What's wrong, Lapu-chan?
実は、もうすぐ吾輩の生誕ライブがあるんですけど、よかったらノエルさんにも出てほしいなって...
Actually, my birthday concert is coming up soon, and I was hoping you could perform in it...
えー！ラプちゃん誘ってくれるの！？嬉しい！もちろん行くよ！
Wow, you're inviting me, Lapu-chan?! I'm so happy! Of course I will!
よーし団長、歌とダンス頑張っちゃおうかな！先輩として、かっこいいところ見せちゃうよー！！！
Alright, the Commander will do her absolute best in singing and dancing! As your senior, I'll show you my cool side!
あ、いや...歌は吾輩がやるんで...ね？ほら、これ持って！
Ah, no... I'll be the one singing... okay? Here, hold this!
え,何に？どういうこと？これってうちわ？
Eh? What? What do you mean? Is this a cheering fan?
さて、あとは何を歌うかですね...
Now, all that's left is deciding what to sing...
一曲目はね、きっとノエルさんも喜んでくれるはず！
For the first song, I'm sure Noel-san will love it!
え！？団長が！？
Eh?! Me?!
去年からノエルさんの影響からか、吾輩のファン層が広がって、こういう曲が喜んでもらえるかなー！って思って！
Since last year, maybe because of your influence, my fanbase has grown, so I thought they'd love a song like this!
えー！期待しちゃうけど...いいのお！？
Wow! You're making me look forward to it... Is it really okay?!
良いですよー！一曲目盛り上がっていきましょー！
Of course! Let's get hyped for the first song!
存外見掛け倒しな虚勢張ってるロマンス
A romance that is surprisingly just for show
組み替えちゃって遺伝子
Rearranging my genes
トゥケトゥケな電波に乗った感情論
An emotional theory riding on high-tension radio waves
僕のアッピル見逃さないでよ
Don't miss my appeal
人間なんてだれだって こういうのが好きなんだって
Everyone, no matter who, likes this kind of stuff
一人善がりオーガズミネイション 溢れてドヴァドヴァ
A self-indulgent orgasm-nation, overflowing like crazy!
年季入りなあざとさ 「好き」の塗りたくり
With well-practused cuteness, painting over with "love"
決めるぜ僕の八点ラヴ ヴァリガルマンダ
I'll settle it with my 8-point Love, Varigarmanda!
おー！
Oh!
膨らんじゃった やばおぴ加減 最高潮ののをくれてやる
It's all swollen up! I'll give you my climax at its absolute peak!
「好き」って言葉で嬲って
Tease me with the word "love"
迎え撃つから 君のアイデンティティティティーン
I'll counter it with your identity-ty-teen!
侮らないで 夢見がちボーイ
Don't underestimate me, dreamy boy!
意外とありなんだって 気付いて
Realize that it's surprisingly acceptable
妄想フラストレイション 毛頭暴走止まらない
Delusional frustration, my hair-trigger rampage won't stop
ギガンティック
Gigantic!
よそ見厳禁 見ててててね？
No looking away, keep your eyes on me, okay?
ラプちゃん！最高だー！
Lapu-chan! You're the best!
もっと輝いてくれー！
Shine even brighter!
可愛いぞー！
You're so cute!
で目覚めて恋に落ちたりなんかして
Waking up and falling in love
わし掴んでシークレット
Grabbing hold of the secret
あなんだやっぱり単純で
Ah, as I thought, it's so simple
僕にとって僕が揺るぎない絶対王政
For me, I am the unwavering absolute monarchy
だからね君だって僕が大好きでしょ？
So you must love me too, right?
見せたげる聖域 僕だけの領域
I'll show you my sanctuary, a domain just for me
息遣いドキドキ優しくして baka
My breathing is throbbing, so be gentle, you dummy
山盛りなあいうぉんちゅ
A mountain-high "I want you"
アガっちゃって恥じらっちゃって
Getting excited and feeling shy
狂っちゃえばイージーモード
If you go crazy, it's easy mode
油断大敵マジモード
Negligence is a great enemy, serious mode
とろとろに溶かして愛need you
Melting you into goo, I need your love
誤算過ぎた僕のエラートラップ
My error trap was too much of a miscalculation
ここは限界突破ラブゲーム
This is a limit-breaking love game
加速しちゃってやばおぴ加減 最高超のを見せてやれ
Accelerating! Show me your climax at its absolute peak!
駆け引き上手な僕がルール
I'm good at bargaining, and I make the rules
狙い撃ち君をプラマイプラスで
Targeting and shooting you with a plus-minus-plus
引き返せない二人だけの秘密
A secret only for the two of us with no turning back
意外とありかもなんて気付いた？罪作りラブポーション
Did you realize it might actually be okay? A sinful love potion
一切合切とめどないギガンティック
Unstoppable, completely gigantic!
目移りなんて許さないね？
No looking away from me, okay?
ギガンティックO.T.Nの略称は
The abbreviation of Gigantic O.T.N
主におちんちんを指す言葉として使われており、男女共用である。
is mainly used to refer to a penis, and is unisex.
はっ！ちょっと！ダメだよ！
Ah! Wait! That's bad!
これ！配信のって...大丈夫！
Is this... really okay for the stream?!
最近では携帯用おちんちんなども開発されており
Recently, portable ones have also been developed
多種多様な活躍を見せており、プライベートなどで楽しむおちんちんを取り戻すため
and they are used in various ways. To reclaim the penises we enjoy in private,
ああ、ちょっと、だめ、だめ！
Ah, wait, no, no!
ラプちゃん！そんなの言っちゃ...！
Lapu-chan! You shouldn't say that...!
全く持って不都合な！
It's completely inconvenient!
あ、BANされる！BANされちゃう！
Ah, we're going to get banned! We're gonna get banned!
全く持って不都合な！ちんちんちんちんちんちんちんちんちん！！！
It's completely inconvenient! Penis penis penis...!!!
膨らんじゃった やばおぴ加減 最高潮ののをくれてやる
It's all swollen up! I'll give you my climax at its absolute peak!
「好き」って言葉で嬲って
Tease me with the word "love"
迎え撃つから 君のアイデンティティティティーン
I'll counter it with your identity-ty-teen!
侮らないで 夢見がちボーイ
Don't underestimate me, dreamy boy!
意外とありなんだって 気付いて
Realize that it's surprisingly acceptable
妄想フラストレイション 毛頭暴走止まらない
Delusional frustration, my hair-trigger rampage won't stop
ギガンティック
Gigantic!
指切りげんまん嘘ついたら 40ピストル
Pinky swear, if you lie, forty pistols!
乱れ打ち
Wild flailing!
はぁ... ラブくんの時代が来た...
Sigh... The era of Lap-sama has finally come...
ショタかわちーよ！
He's so cute!
ラブくん、輝いてる！
Lap-sama, you're shining!
最後まで輝いて！
Keep shining until the very end!
さすがに先輩をファン扱いするのはどうかと思いますよ？
I'm not sure if treating your senior as a fan is appropriate...
いや、ノエルさんはファンでしょ！ファンっていうか、ママになろうとしてる人...？
No way, Noel-san is definitely a fan! Or rather, someone who's trying to be my mommy...?
とにかく、めっちゃ盛り上がってましたやん！
Anyway, it was incredibly hype!
てかてかお姉さんといえば、ホロライブって学校みたいじゃない？
Come to think of it, when it comes to older sisters, doesn't Hololive feel like a school?
学校？
A school?
学校のみんなのアイドル... そらさん
The school idol... Sora-san.
隣のクラスの留学生... キアラさん
The foreign exchange student in the next class... Kiara-san.
凛とした清楚な先輩... AZKiさん
The dignified, pure senior... AZKi-san.
部活の先輩お姉さま... ネリッサ
The older sister senior in the club... Nerissa.
クールビューティーな先生... クロニー
The cool beauty teacher... Kronii.
そして、同じクラスにいる、うるさい幼馴染の同級生... いろは
And the noisy childhood friend classmate in the same class... Iroha.
そうだ！これをライブでやれば、盛り上がること間違いなし！
That's it! If we do this live, it'll definitely be super hype!
そうと決まれば早速突撃だー！
Now that it's decided, let's charge right in!
次から次へとすごい行動力だ...
She moves onto the next thing so fast...
いろはー！
Iroha!
うん？なんでござるか？
Hmm? What is it de gozaru?
ライブでやりたい曲あるんだけど、見ててくんない？
I have a song I want to perform live. Can you watch me?
？？？見る？？？どういうことでござる？
Watch? What do you mean by that?
そう！見るだけ！やっぱり幼馴染と言えば、いつでも見守ってくれる存在だからね...
Yeah, just watch! As my childhood friend, you're the one who always watches over me...
ただそこにいるだけで良い、そばにいてくれるだけ、その温かさが染みるんだ
Just being there is enough, just staying by my side. I can feel your warmth...
え... なんか気持ち悪いでござる...
Uh... That's kind of creepy, de gozaru...
いいからいいから！さ、行くぞー！
Never mind that! Alright, here we go!
横画面で開始します(画面表記)
[Starting in landscape mode]
え？
Huh?
な、これ？
What's this?
な、な、これ？
What... What is this?
な、これ？な、な、な、なこれ？
What is this? Wh-Wh-What on earth is this?!
え？何？
Huh? What?
何？何？
What? What?
何、何、え？
What? What? Huh?
いろはさん？
Iroha-san?
おお？
Whoa?
おお、おお？
Whoa, whoa?
おお？あれ？何？え？
Whoa? Wait, what? Huh?
とりあえずキミに結構
For now, I'm pretty...
トキメキトキメキスモールド
...thumping and throbbing for you!
いやいやいや、別に好きとかそんなんじゃないよ！
No, no, no! It's not like I like you or anything!
ただちょっとちょっとちょっと 目でおっかけてるだけだってば！
I'm just chasing you with my eyes a little bit, okay?!
別にキミに結構メロメロなんだってば
It's not like I'm totally head over heels for you...
勉強も全然頭に入ってこなくて
...or that I can't concentrate on studying at all!
ヤバイヤバイ
This is bad, this is bad!
キミにインスパイアされて
I'm inspired by you!
はききって！はききって！
Spit it out! Spit it out!
こんな罰ゲームの腹いせに こうやってキミが直接私の目の前に来ると... いってきます！
To get back at this penalty game, with you right in front of me like this... here I go!
こわいって！
This is scary!
やめっ...
Stop...
やべえ！
This is bad!
おい！
Hey!
そういうことね...
So that's how it is...
違うライブ...
This is a different live performance...
やべえ、やべえ
This is bad, this is bad...
違う...
No...
やめろって言ってんだろ！
I told you to stop!
はい、いいんだ
Yes, it's fine.
ピピピピッとブースト マチュピチュ遺跡に遺跡に
Pi-pi-pi-pi, boost! To the Machu Picchu ruins, ruins...
死にのってぷっくぷくの波死に
Riding death, a bubbly wave of death...
大、大、大、大、大混雑
Major, major, major congestion...
なかなかなかなかなかなかドキドキしちゃう
My heart keeps thumping and thumping...
キミのキミのキミのキミのキミのキミの
Of you, of you, of you, of you...
おっきいミス！
A big mistake!
ミスして！もっとミスして！
Make a mistake! Make more mistakes!
もっとミスして！もっとミスして！
Make more mistakes! Make more mistakes!
ミスしてミスしてミスして A B C D E F G オツ！
Mistake, mistake, mistake, A-B-C-D-E-F-G, good job!
黙らっしゃい！ちょっと黙らっしゃい！もう我慢できない！
Shut up! Just shut up a bit! I can't take it anymore!
したしたしゅんききてそとコラコラもう！
Under, under, puberty is here, hey, hey, enough already!
怒らしちゃダメか？え？
I shouldn't make them mad? Huh?
3万年のピチピチのお肌で拍手喝采先輩
Applause with your 30,000-year-old youthful skin, Senior!
そんなに顔近づけられたら もう溶けちゃいそう真ん中って
If you bring your face so close, I feel like I'm melting in the middle!
そして生理の隙間キラリして 1、2、3、4、5、6
And then sparkling in the gaps of organization, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
スタート1,000ちょっとで最高みちゃった最高
Starting just over 1,000, I saw the absolute best...
ちょっと、何してんのよ！
Wait, what are you doing?!
乱れ打ち！えーえーえー、ご褒防！
Wild flailing! And a reward!
自分でやるのそれ？
Are you doing that yourself?!
自分でやるの！
I'm doing it myself!
にんにくの生姜焼き
Garlic ginger pork!
先輩にお届け
Delivering to my senior!
上に行って 下に行って
Go up, go down...
スパイラル地上1階地下4階 このテンションもう止められない！
Spiral first floor, basement fourth floor, this tension can't be stopped!
どっちを選ぶの？
Which one are you going to choose?!
選びなさいよ！
Make your choice!
ち、違う！これは、イマジナリーお姉さん...
N-No, wait! These are imaginary older sisters...
どっちも？
Are you choosing both?!
いや、どっちもとかじゃなくて...
No, it's not both...
すみませんでした！
I am so sorry!
ピピピピッとブースト マチュピチュ遺跡に遺跡に
Pi-pi-pi-pi, boost! To the Machu Picchu ruins, ruins...
死にのってぷっくぷくのブレーキ死に抜け上がり
Riding death, a bubbly brake, escaping death...
だめだめだめだめだめだめクラッとしちゃう
No, no, no, my head is spinning...
俺の俺の俺の俺の俺の俺のファッキング！
My, my, my, my, my fucking...
こいして！もっとこいして！
Love me! Love me more!
もっとこいして！もっとこいして！
Love me more! Love me more!
こいしてこいしてこいして A B C D E F G オツ！
Love me, love me, love me, A-B-C-D-E-F-G, good job!
立て引いてちょっと引いてやっぱ危険 P P
Stand back, pull back a bit, as expected, it's dangerous, P P!
下下としごろそれそとコラコラもう！
Under, under, puberty, hey, hey, enough already!
ちょっとだけねぇ、ちょっとだけ見せて、ちょっとだけ、ほら
Just a little, hey, show me just a little, just a little, come on...
ちょっと男子！
Excuse me, boys!
ちょっとだけねぇ、ちょっとだけ見せて、ちょっとだけ、あと何やってる？
Just a little, hey, show me just a little, just a little... and what are you doing?
何何何何何！
What, what, what, what, what?!
せーの、あわせて、あわせて！
One, two, put them together, put them together!
いいよ、いいよ、おおおおお！
Nice, nice! Ohhhhh!
あわせて、はい、はい！
Put them together, yes, yes!
おお、わあ、わあ！
Oh, wow, wow!
いいよ、せーの、ああ...
Nice, one, two, ah...
あー！
Ah!
手を合わせてください、はい！
Please put your hands together, yes!
みんな元気にいただきます
Everyone, let's cheerfully say 'itadakimasu'!
いきます
Let's go!
さようなら
Goodbye!
お疲れ様でした
Thank you for your hard work!
いってらっしゃい
Have a safe trip!
皆さま
Everyone,
おぺこー！
Opeko-!
元気すぎるだろ…
Way too energetic...
いっせーのーで！うしろまえ！
Ready, set, go! Back to front!
まわれ旋風 精神精神
Spin, whirlwind, spirit, spirit!
のってけのってけ ドロドロの
Ride along, ride along, this gooey...
大・大・大混雑
super, super, super crowd!
にゃかにゃか にゃにゃにゃか
Nyaka-nyaka, nya-nya-nyaka...
はてさて？ あいたたた
Well now? Ouch, ouch, ouch!
きみの きみの きみの きみの
Your, your, your, your...
お・し・お・き！
P-U-N-I-S-H-M-E-N-T!
みせて みせて もっとみせて
Show me, show me, show me more!
みせて みせて ちょっとみせて
Show me, show me, show me a bit!
みせて みせて みせて みせて
Show me, show me, show me, show me!
A B C D いいお返事
A B C D, give me a good answer!
がまん がまん ちょっとがまん
Endure, endure, endure a bit!
やっぱがまんできないし
Actually, I can't hold it in anymore!
したしたした執着で
With dripping, dripping, dripping obsession,
そと ころ ころ ころん
softly rolling, rolling over...
S-U-I-B-I-M-U UI-BEAM!
これアネモネの曲だけど、大丈夫そう？
This is Anemone's song, but is she gonna be okay?
あ、最後までね！最後までね！お疲れ様です！
Ah, until the end! Until the end! Thank you!
きついけど、最後までー！
It's tough, but until the end!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
まじでいろはすビジネスでよかったー
I'm seriously glad Iroha-Su is just business...
ぎむ、ぎむ、バイバイ
Duty, duty. Bye-bye.
じゃあね、帰るね
See ya, I'm heading home.
どうしたんですか？
What's wrong?
ねえねえ！プロデューサーの好みってどんな人なん？
Hey, hey! What kind of person is your type, Producer?
え～…
Well...
ほら、ホロライブっていろんな人いるじゃん？
I mean, there are all kinds of people in Hololive, right?
しゅぴびしゅわー、すうの充電足りてるー？水宮すうだよー！
Shupibishuwar! Is Su's charge enough? It's Mizumiya Su!
わっしょーい！ホロライブの清楚担当！みんなのアイドル！夏色まつりでーす！
Wasshoi! The pure one of Hololive! Everyone's idol! Natsuiro Matsuri-desu!
みなさん、待ったかね～？ホロライブ6期生、holoXの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します～！
Did you wait, everyone? Hololive 6th gen, holoX's female executive, Takane Lui-desu!
はーい、みなさま～、こんらみ～！ホロライブ5期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！
Hi, everyone, Kon-Lamy! Hololive 5th gen's liver-faced, Yukihana Lamy-desu!
Good evening! My cute students. ちょこーん！ホロライブ2期生、悪魔のバーチャル保健医、癒月ちょこでーす！ちょこーん！
Good evening! My cute students. Chocoon! Hololive 2nd gen, demon virtual school nurse, Yuzuki Choco-desu! Chocoon!
Ahoy! ホロライブ3期生、宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンですぅー！
Ahoy! Hololive 3rd gen, Houshou Pirate Captain Houshou Marine-desu!
みなさんとても魅力的ですよ？
Everyone is very charming, you know?
いやいや、そういうんじゃないでしょ。
No, no, that's not what I mean.
いやぁ…仕事ですからね。ホロライブの方で…とかはないですよ。
Well... it's my job. So having someone from Hololive... is out of the question.
ふーん。
Hmph.
ただ、最近の趣味といえば…
Though, speaking of my recent hobbies...
＊＊＊＊＊
*****
え…。
Eh...
いや…それは…さすがに…すごい趣味してるな。
No... that's... as expected... a really wild hobby.
この人に言われたくないな…
I don't want to hear that from you...
あ！こんな時間じゃん！吾輩ちょっとこの後用事あるんで、じゃーね！
Ah! Look at the time! I have something to do after this, so see ya!
初めて４万いったぜ…
For the first time, it reached 40,000...
やべぇ…
Man...
高かった…
That was expensive...
でも可愛かったから、いっか！
But since she was cute, I guess it's fine!
ジャケットとか、クリーニングしちゃった…
I even got my jacket dry-cleaned...
着ちゃった…
And I wore it...
おいっ
Wait...
はっ！
Ah!
え？
Eh?
これですか？
Is it this?
写真とちょっと違いますけど
She's a bit different from the photo...
えー？
Ehh?
え？
Eh?
チェンジ チェンジ チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change, change, change! No thank you!
それじゃちょっと息抜きでもしましょうかって感じで
"Then let's take a little breather," in that kind of mood,
チラシの番号に手
reaching for the number on the flyer.
たまたまドンピシャで気に入った子がいたんで
I happened to find a girl who was exactly my type,
胸の大きいのをチョイス
so I chose one with a big chest.
髪型ショートで攻めるのが得意な子
A girl with short hair, who is good at taking the initiative.
今からそちらへお送りいたします
"We will send her over to you right now."
ドアを開けたら別れた彼女
When I opened the door, it was my ex-girlfriend!
おいおいこいつは痛い何の冗談だ
Whoa, whoa, what kind of painful joke is this?!
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た
I called a delivery health service and you came!
うつろな目をして立っていた
Standing there with hollow eyes...
あなたの好みのタイプになって帰ってきましたって
"I've come back having become your favorite type," she said.
ロミジュリばりの悲劇におい
Smelling like a Romeo and Juliet-style tragedy.
傷つきましてはとりいそぎと
"Since I was hurt, for the time being..."
街頭を見渡して
Looking around the streetlights,
大声で さあ
and shouting out loud, now!
チェンジ チェンジ チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change, change, change! No thank you!
朝の遅く…
In the late morning...
あ、今日はご機嫌
Ah, how are you
いかがですか、お嬢
feeling today, young lady?
なかなかの塩梅で
Quite in a good mood.
隣の部屋 喘ぐの声 大声
The loud moans from the room next door
ホラ今も
Look, even right now...
BPM192で
At a BPM of 192,
妄想にスレンダーな横顔描いたから
since I drew a slender profile in my delusions.
たまにはお利口な子を我が儘な子にしようか
Sometimes, let's make this good girl a selfish one.
ドアを開けたら新人だかの彼女
When I opened the door, there was a girl, maybe a rookie.
おいおい、どんな魔法を使っちゃってんだよ
Hey, what kind of magic are you playing on me?
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た
I called a delivery health and you came.
虚ろな目をして立ってたんだ
Standing there with a blank look in your eyes.
あなたの好みのタイプは全部わかっているのよって
Saying, "I know exactly the kind of girl you like."
制服、人妻、ナース、OL
Uniform, housewife, nurse, office lady...
熟女、スク水、お好み全部登場
Mature woman, school swimsuit, all your favorites appear!
オプションは頼まない
I won't ask for options,
延長もしない
and I won't extend the time!
行くぞーー！せーの！
Let's go! One, two!
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change! Change! Change! No thank you!
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た
I called a delivery health and you came.
虚ろな目をして立ってたんだ
Standing there with a blank look in your eyes.
あなたの好みのタイプになって帰って来ましたって
Saying, "I've come back having changed into your preferred type!"
思い出したくもない笑顔がトラウマとなって住み着いた
That smile, which I don't even want to remember, has turned into trauma and settled in.
タクシーを見送って絶賛逃亡中さ、せーの！
I watched the taxi leave and I'm currently on the run! One, two!
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change! Change! Change! No thank you!
まさか
No way...
ボツだな
This is a reject.
いや、いいんだよ、プロデューサーの好みとか！
No, I don't care about your preferences, Producer!
聞いたのは、そっちです。
But you were the one who asked.
ちょっとちょっと、ケンカしてどうしたの！
Whoa, whoa! What are you two fighting about?
あっ、こよちゃん！！！聞いてよ！プロデューサーのやつが〜！！！
Ah, Koyo-chan!!! Listen to this! The Producer is being such a—!!!
うん、うん
Yeah, yeah.
それで、あいつがさ〜〜！！
And then he said—!!
そうだね〜ラプちゃん辛かったね〜
I know~ That must've been so tough on you, Lapu-chan~
はぁ、ここまでいろんなホロメンと絡んできたけど
Sigh, I've interacted with so many Hololive members so far,
やっぱりこよちゃんが一番だよ！！
but Koyo-chan is definitely the best!!
そうだ！今度の吾輩の生誕ライブ一緒に出ようよ！
I know! Let's perform together in my upcoming birthday live concert!
こよちゃんと吾輩にぴったりな曲があるんだ！
There's a song that is absolutely perfect for us!
ライブの出演ね
A live performance, huh?
うん、スケジュール確認しておくね〜！
Yeah! I'll check my schedule, okay?
ありがとー！
Thank you!
じゃあまたステージで！！
See you on stage then!
（俺、このライブが終わったら…君と…）
(Once this live concert is over... I will... with you...)
横画面で開始します
[Starting in landscape mode]
時計の針が12から12に回るまで
The hands on the clock spin all the way from twelve to twelve
頭の中が染められていく ぴんこすてぃっくLuv
While my mind is dyed pink by this pink stick love
すれ違ったり ふと目と目が交わるだけで
Just passing by each other or having our eyes meet...
宙に浮いてる気分になる
To make me feel like I am floating on air
demo_sonna_koto_kimi_wa_shiranai_shi
But there is no way you'd know my feelings at all
手を繋ぎたい キスをしたい
I wanna hold hands and kiss too,
君と半径10メートル以内で
within a ten-meter radius of you.
だから妄想で
But it won't come true, so in my delusions
今日も蛇口とキスの練習day
Today is another day practicing kisses with a faucet.
君のことに とことん一喜一憂 だって好きだから
Going through a rollercoaster of emotions because I like you
だから
That's why,
こっち向いて 待って待って やっぱ向いて
Look my way! Wait, wait! Look over here,
独り占めしたいの
I want you all to myself.
こっち向いて わがままだってわかってるけど だってだってだってだって
Look my way! I know it's selfish, but because, because...
目が合って 高鳴って 赤くなって 百面相してるの
Our eyes meet, my heart pounds, my face turns red, making crazy faces.
今日だって 君のせいで ドキドキ忙しい
Even today, because of you, my heart is pounding like crazy!
どうしてくれるの
What are you going to do about it?
サンデー マンデー ちゅーして ぎゅーして
Sunday, Monday, give me a kiss and a hug
毎日クリンチ射抜いてけ窮地 健気さキューティ
Clenching tight every day to pierce through the distress, a cute devotion
一途にウォッチ あっちそっちこっち向いてどっち？
Looking single-mindedly, over there, over here, which way?
早まる鼓動のbpm 日に日に好きになるsml
My heartbeat's accelerating BPM, liking you more and more, SML
わかったよなんて自分勝手 やっぱりきっぱりとびっきりのLuv
Say "I get it," how selfish, but it's definitely an extraordinary love
新鮮なこの思いトゥインクル ピンクを君に伝えたい
This fresh feeling twinkles, I want to convey this pink to you
ピンクスの脳内占拠レベルは最強 手付かず勉強許して？ご愛嬌
My brain's "Pinkus" occupation level is the strongest, please forgive my neglected studies! As a charm
胸のときめきも絶頂！ 待ちに待った今日 君とランデブーご一緒なんて
The throbbing in my chest is at its peak! Today is the long-awaited day to rendezvous with you
妄想で済ます憂いの生 テンション！
Ending it as a delusion, a life of grief, high tension!
こっち向いて まってまって やっぱ向いて 恥ずかしいけど
Look this way, wait wait, actually look at me, although it's embarrassing
こっち向いて 君の目に映った 自分の顔が赤い気がして
I feel like my face reflected in your eyes is turning red
目が合って 手が触れた それだけで 一大事件なんだもん
Our eyes met, our hands touched, just that alone is a major event!
ねえだって 君のことが この先どうしてなのか言えないの
Hey because of you, why is it that I can't say what comes next?
まぶたの裏思い浮かべて
Picturing you behind my closed eyelids
すきだよ すきなのね おもうだけで しあわせなの ほんとはちょっと せつない
I love you, I really do, just thinking of you makes me happy, though it's actually a little painful
くちをでるつよがり みみをふさぎさびしがり
Showing off with empty words, blocking my ears, feeling lonely
じつはもうげんかい こえてんのだけど
To tell you the truth, I've already passed my limit, though
いえるはずない いえるわけない おくびょうなハートに あとおしして ワンツースリー！
There's no way I can say it, my cowardly heart, give me a push, one, two, three!
こっち向いて まってまって やっぱ向いて 独り占めしたいの
Look this way, wait wait, actually look at me, I want you all to myself
こっち向いて わがままだって わかってるけど だってだってだってだって
Look this way, I know it's selfish, but but but but...
目が合って 高鳴って 赤くなって
Our eyes met, my heart racing, turning red
百面相してるの 今日だって君のせいで ドキドキ忙しい
Showing a kaleidoscope of faces, today too because of you, my pounding heart is so busy
神様お願い ちょっとでいいから 勇気をください
Please God, even just a little is fine, give me some courage
かじきまぐろ チョー！
Swordfish, extreme!
プロデューサー、あああ！！！
Producer, ahhh!!!
どうしたんですか？
What is the matter?
こよちゃんにフラれたぁ〜
Koyo-chan rejected me!
フラれるとかあるんですね？
So it is possible for you to get rejected?
ちくしょう！！！こうなったら！！！
Damn it!!! In that case!!!
嫌な予感がする
I have a bad feeling about this.
誰でもいいから付き合いたいー！！
I don't care who, I just want to date someone!!!
そうなったらもう終わりですよ
If you've resorted to that, you're doomed.
うるさい！
Shut up!
吾輩は…彼女作って幸せになるんだー！！！！
I'm... gonna find a girlfriend and become happy!!!
横画面で開始します
[Starting in landscape mode]
やるぞ。緊張する。やってやるぞ。
Let's do this. I'm nervous. I'm gonna do this.
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me
もう誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
男の前ではしゃべれても
I can talk perfectly fine in front of guys
女の前ではしゃべれない
But I can't talk when I'm in front of girls
トラウマだらけの僕の過去
My trauma-littered history
涙なしでは語れない
I cannot recount without tears in my eyes
どうして彼女ができないの
Why can't I get a girlfriend?
吾輩は素敵と君は言う
"I think you're a wonderful person," you say to me
それなら吾輩と付き合ってよ
Then why not go out with me?
その苦笑いの意味は何
What is the meaning of that awkward smile?
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me
もう誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me
もう誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me
もう誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
なんで！？なんでだよぉ〜〜〜！
Why?! Why is this happening?!
全員からフラれたぁ〜〜〜！！！
I got rejected by literally everyone!!!
うーん、このライブ、大丈夫かな
Hmm, is this concert gonna be alright?
くそ、もうこうなったら！
Damn it, if it's come to this!
ええ！？なんですかそれ！
Eh?! What is that?!
この封印を…解放してやるぅ！！！
I'll... unleash this seal!!!
俺の聖域を…爆裂させてやるぅ！！！うおーーー！！！
I'll make my Sanctuary... explode!!! Uwooooh!!!
お、おしまいだこのライブは…もはやライブなのかも怪しい所…
I-It's all over for this concert... I'm not even sure if this is a concert anymore...
なんていうか大きな声で言うことではないかもしれませんが
I shouldn't really say this out loud, but...
男女に備わったあれとそれ
there's "this and that" between men and women...
正と乱のいわばあれとそれ そんなこんなで起こるハプニング
The pure and chaotic "this and that"... and all the happenings that arise,
あっという間に僕のエンディング
before I know it, it's my ending.
謝って 悩んで 困ってしまって どうしようってなにもできない無常
Apologizing, worrying, in trouble, "What should I do?" There's nothing I can do, how transient...
0.02mmの壁がすげーもどかしくなって
This 0.02mm barrier is getting so frustrating,
真っ赤なマイサンシャイン
my bright red sunshine,
すぐに入れたくなるのは君の性
wanting to put it in right away is just your nature.
いいじゃーんとかそんな気分で迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンで
Saying "Why not?" we welcomed each other in that heaven,
あ、しままったって思ったってもう遅い
ah, even if we regret it, it's too late.
アップサイド・インサイド・アウト アイデフェンチュー 甘噛みユーの髪
Upside, inside out, I defend you, gently biting your hair,
いっさいがっさいは愛で返事 アイムカミン ユーカミン
everything is answered with love, I'm coming, you're coming.
待ってこれって僕のせい？ 生でいいよって言った君のせい？
Wait, is this my fault? Or is it your fault for saying "without it is fine"?
そして5分で終わるテストって 信憑性欠けるもんだって
And a test that ends in five minutes is so untrustworthy,
しっかり刻まれた十字架に 貼り付けられた僕は切り捨てに
nailed to a deeply engraved cross, I was cast aside.
なったって無理ってわかっているって どうしようって何もできない
I know it's impossible now, what can I do? I can do nothing.
0.02mmの壁がすげー悩ましくなって
This 0.02mm barrier is getting so troublesome,
真っ青なマイサンシャイン
my deep blue sunshine,
すぐに入れたくなるのは僕のせい
wanting to put it in right away is my fault.
大丈夫とかそんな気分で 甲斐性もないこんな身分で
With a "It's fine" feeling, in this state with no reliability,
泣いたって怒ったって 後の祭り
crying or getting angry, it's too late.
マキシマムインサートなう
Maximum insert now.
アーユーレディ？ 愛撫ハニー指噛み
Are you ready? Loving honey, finger biting,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Holy Lance Explosion Boy,
愛のフィーリング アイハブハニーユービカミン
love feeling, I have honey, you be coming.
遠い夏の思い出
Memories of a distant summer...
君の長い髪が揺れる
your long hair sways.
待ってこれって僕のせい？ 中に出してって言った君のせい？
Wait, is this my fault? Or is it your fault for saying "put it inside"?
そして5分で終わるテストって 絶対的二次元論だって
And a test that ends in five minutes is an absolute dualism,
十月十日ばかりの運命を 支配している僕は神様に
controlling a destiny of ten months, to God, I...
なれないって無理ってわかっていて 結局何も解決してない
know I can't become one, it's impossible, in the end nothing is resolved.
0.02mmの壁がすげーもどかしくなって
This 0.02mm barrier is getting so frustrating,
真っ白なマイサンシャイン
my pure white sunshine,
すぐに入れたくなるのは君の性
wanting to put it in right away is just your nature.
いいじゃーんとかそんな気分で迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンで
Saying "Why not?" we welcomed each other in that heaven,
あ、しままったって思ったってもう遅い
ah, even if we regret it, it's too late.
アップサイド・インサイド・アウト アイデフェンチュー
Upside, inside out, I defend you,
甘噛みユーの髪
gently biting your hair,
いっさいがっさいは愛で返事
everything is answered with love,
アイムカミン ユーカミン
I'm coming, you're coming.
マキシマムインサートなう アーユーレディ？
Maximum insert now, are you ready?
愛撫ハニー指噛み
Loving honey, finger biting,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Holy Lance Explosion Boy,
愛のフィーリング アイハブハニーユービカミン
love feeling, I have honey, you be coming.
いやあ、まさか、聖槍でライブ会場壊しちゃうなんて
Wow, I can't believe the Holy Lance would destroy the venue.
つい…力を解放してしまった…
I accidentally... released my power...
それにしても、みんなど酷くない？吾輩を振るなんて…
Still, isn't everyone a bit too cruel? Turning me down like that...
もうやってらんないよ～
I can't take this anymore!
ここはあの手を使うしかない
(I have no choice but to use *that* trick.)
ラプラスさん、実は、あの方に来ていただきます！
Laplus-san, actually, I've invited that person to come here!
あの方？
That person?
ラブくん？どうしたのー？
Lapu-kun? What's wrong?
うわっ！？あ、あ、あじゅ姉！？まさか、吾輩のために来てくれたの？？？？
Whoa?! A-A-Aju-nee?! Did you really come here for me????
当然だよー！だって今日は、ラブくんの誕生日でしょー？
Of course! Because today is your birthday, right, Lapu-kun?
あ、やばい、吾輩今日が命日かもしれん…
Ah, oh no, today might be the anniversary of my death...
お誕生日おめでとう！プレゼントは何がいいのかな～？
Happy Birthday! I wonder what you'd like for a present?
え！プレゼントってなんでももらえるの？！
Eh! I can get absolutely anything as a present?!
あじゅがあげられるものなら何でも大丈夫だゾ☆
As long as it's something I can give, anything is fine!☆
えー！！えええ！じゃあ…
Really!! Whoa! Then...
え？今なんて言ったの？変な音で聞こえなかった！
Eh? What did you just say? I couldn't hear over that weird noise!
あれ？
Huh?
なんだこれー！届かないぞ吾輩の願いが！
What is this?! My wish isn't getting through!
あぶない…危うく配信できないところだった…
(That was close... We almost couldn't stream this...)
邪魔するなプロデューサーーー！！！！！
Don't interfere, Producer!!!!!
なんか色々大変そうだから…今日はこの辺で帰るね！今日は本当におめでとー！ラブくん、また遊ぼうね～
It seems like a lot is going on... so I'll head home for today! Happy birthday again! Let's play again, Lapu-kun~
帰るね。
I'm going home.
今日は本当におめでとう！
Happy birthday today!
ラプくん、また遊ぼうね〜
Lap-kun, let's play again!
あ、あじゅねぇ！あじゅねええええええ！！！
Ah, Aju-nee! Aju-neeeeee!!!
え、はい。はい、分かりました！
Yes, yes. I understand!
ラプラスさん！新曲オーディションですって！
Laplus-san! They said there is a new song audition!
どゆこと？
What do you mean?
新曲だけのオーディション大会があって、そこで優勝したら、大型コラボですって！
There is an audition for new songs only, and if you win, you get a big collaboration!
今すぐ曲準備します！
I'll prepare the song right away!
ダンスレッスンいれますね！
I'll schedule some dance lessons!
今から新曲？ダンスレッスン？
A new song starting now? Dance lessons?
ま、間に合うのそれ？もうライブまでちょっとしかないよ？
W-Will we make it in time? There's barely any time left before the concert!
間に合わせてください！もしオーディションに合格したら大型コラボなんですよ！
Please make it in time! If you pass the audition, it's a huge collaboration!
えー！我が輩も疲れたんですけど！大型コラボってなんなの？
What?! I'm already tired! What is this big collaboration anyway?
それはまだ秘密です。
That is still a secret.
なんでだよおおおお！！！
Why is that?!
体力ないって言ってるのに、走り込み…？
I told you I have no stamina, so why am I running...?
だからこその走り込みです！
That's exactly why you're running!
この筋トレ、本当に意味あるの？
Is this muscle training really meaningful?
よし！良い感じだ！
Alright! Looking good!
ラプラスさん！本番前に行きましょう！あの方の元へ！
Laplus-san! Let's go before the show starts! To that person's place!
あ、あの方！？よし、行こう！！
Th-That person?! Alright, let's go!!
チョコ先生！！！
Choco-sensei!!!
あら、いらっしゃい、ラプちゃん。
Oh, welcome, Lap-chan.
どれにするの？
Which one are you going for?
うーん…悩んじゃうよね。
Hmm... it's hard to choose, isn't it?
わかる、わかる。
I know, I know.
答えは一つじゃないからね。
Because there isn't just one answer.
ラプちゃん、真鍵に考えてるのね。
Lap-chan is thinking so seriously.
え？全部ちゃんと見たいの？
Eh? You want to look at everything properly?
じゃあ、皆さんお待ちかねのグッズ情報よ！ラプちゃん！
Well then, here is the merch info everyone's been waiting for! Lap-chan!
はい！はいはいはい！
Yes! Yes yes yes!
ラプラス・ダークネス誕生日記念2026グッズ！順番に紹介していきます！
Laplus Darkness Birthday Commemorative 2026 Merch! I'll introduce them in order!
じゃん！まずはこちら！カードアルバム！
Ta-da! First up, this! Card Album!
特典のあの、チェキ風ブロマイドカードとか、ホロカとかを収納できるアルバムです！
It's an album that can store those polaroid-style bromide cards, Holoca, and so on!
えっ、めっちゃ久しぶりに三輪くろね先生が、我が輩のママ、くろねママが描き下ろしてくれました！イラスト！
For the first time in a while, Miwano Kuroki-sensei—my mama, Kuroki-mama—drawn an illustration for us!
イェーイ！
Yay!
めっちゃ可愛い！
So cute!
はい、でしょ？
Right?
このアルバムをギュッとしてるのがまたいい。そう、これもちゃんとあのアルバムをギュッとしてるんですよ。あ、売ってるやつを。
The way you're hugging this album is also nice. Yes, I'm hugging that album properly—the actual product on sale.
じゃあこれ買ったら、ラプちゃんがギュッとしたアルバムが手に入るってこと？
So if I buy this, I'll get the album that Lap-chan hugged?
え！？それは、あの、商品法、景品法的に…
Eh?! That is, like, legally speaking under the Premiums and Representations Act...
二つ目はこちら！興奮ボイスキーホルダー！
Second is this! Excitement Voice Keychain!
え、毎回お馴染みの録り下ろしボイスが6種類入ったキーホルダーです！
It's a keychain with 6 newly recorded voices, as usual!
え、押すと声が出ます。いつも通り。今回もしろこ先生の描き下ろしです！
A voice plays when pressed. Same as always. Illustrated by Shiroko-sensei again!
めろめろな表情をしたオリジナルのキーマスコットです。
An original mascot with a lovey-dovey expression.
押すと声が出る？
It plays a voice when pressed?
はい。 / へえ〜！どこを押したらいいのかな〜？
Yes. / Heh~! I wonder where I should press~?
あっ！あー！
Ah! Ah!
み、三つ目は！三つ目は、こちら！
Th-Third is! Third is this!
え、ばぶラプラスぬいぐるみです！
Um, Babu Laplus Plushie!
おしゃぶりをくわえて、ベビウェアを着て寝ている我が輩のぬいぐるみでございます。
It's a plushie of me wearing baby clothes, with a pacifier in my mouth, sleeping.
え、めっちゃ可愛い！
Eh, so cute!
我が輩もギュッてしたい！
I want to hug it tight too!
ちょ、チョコ先生、そんな… / ギュッてしたい！いつでも…いつでも…
Ch-Choco-sensei, please... / I want to hug it! Anytime... anytime...
あ、あ、セクハラ！やめてください！
Ah, ah, sexual harassment! Please stop!
本当に。もう、まずい、まずい。四つ目はこちら！
Seriously. This is bad, bad. Fourth is this!
あ、おくるみ…あ、言っちゃった。え、ばぶラプラスぬいぐるみを包めるハンカチです！
Ah, swaddle... Ah, I said it. Um, it's a handkerchief that can swaddle the Babu Laplus Plushie!
さっきのぬいぐるみをつつめて、あとは普通にハンカチとしても使えます。
You can swaddle the plushie from earlier with it, and otherwise, you can just use it as a normal handkerchief.
あ、じゃあおくるみとして使えるってことね。
Ah, so it can be used as a swaddle.
そうです。
Yes.
可愛い！ / で、デカめです。これくらいしかないです、我が輩の周りには。
Cute! / It's on the larger side. That's about all there is around me.
そして最後に、フルセット購入特典として、三輪くろね先生描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
And finally, as a full-set purchase bonus, a polaroid-style bromide card illustrated by Miwano Kuroki-sensei is included!
はい。そして数量限定バージョンは、はい、書きます、サインを。直筆サインと複製メッセージが入ってます！
Yes. And the limited-quantity version will have—yes, I'll sign it—a handwritten signature and a duplicated message!
通常バージョンは
The regular version...
箔押しの複製サインとメッセージが入ってるよ
includes a foil-stamped replica signature and message!
この配信のあとに販売開始だから
Since sales start after this stream...
みんなよろしくね！
everyone, please support it!
お願いします！
Please do!
はい、以上グッズ紹介なんですけれども
Yes, that's all for the merch introduction!
チョコ先生、ありがとうございました！
Choco-sensei, thank you very much!
こちらこそ！
No, thank you!
これからちょっとオーディションなんで、新曲の。
I have an audition next for a new song.
がんばってきます
I'll go do my best!
応援してるね、ラプちゃん。がんばって！
I'll be rooting for you, Lapu-chan. Good luck!
がんばります！ありがとう！
I'll do my best! Thank you!
がんばれー！
Good luck!
お姉さま♡ラヴコール
[Onee-sama ♡ Love Call]
あ、お姉さま！
Ah, Onee-sama!
あの、今日ライブなのに、我が輩、お風呂入ってないんですけど
Um, even though there's a live concert today, I haven't taken a bath...
お願いがあって、へへっ
But I have a request, hehe...
あの、耳、舐めてほしいです！
Um, I want you to lick my ears!
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Inhale, exhale, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
おーねーえーさーまーー！
O-n-e-e-s-a-m-a!
世の中のお姉さまに捧ぐ
Dedicated to all the Onee-samas in the world
あ、お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Ah, Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
起きたら耳元で囁いて
Whisper in my ear when I wake up
あ、お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Ah, Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
胸元に滴るその汗を
The sweat dripping down your chest...
我が輩のお紅茶に入れてゴックンゴックンしたい！
I want to put it in my tea and gulp it down!
角の角の角 掴んで頂戴
Please grab my horns, my horns, my horns!
ハンドル代わりに おっおおっ
Use them like handles, oh-oh-oh!
あっ、あっ、お姉さまと、視聴者の皆様
Ah, ah, Onee-sama, and all the viewers!
こんな歌、ライブで歌って、ごめんなさい！
I'm so sorry for singing this kind of song live!
あ、お仕置き！お仕置きください！
Ah, punishment! Please punish me!
尻尾から手突っ込んでガタガタ言わしてやってください、角を！
Put your hand up my tail and shake my horns until they rattle!
あっ、お姉さま今日、ニーハイですか！？
Ah, Onee-sama, are you wearing thigh-highs today?!
盛り上がってきましたね！
It's getting really exciting!
え、お姉さま、お姉さま来ちゃう！あ、お姉さま！
Eh, Onee-sama, Onee-sama is coming! Ah, Onee-sama!
あ、お世話になっております！
Thank you always for your kind support!
ありがたや ありがたや ありがたや ほい
Thank heavens, thank heavens, thank heavens!
おいでなすってお姉さま
Welcome, Onee-sama!
雑魚雑魚言ってください
Please call me trash!
残さず飲み込むぞ
I'll swallow it all down!
愛のムチムチ 愛のムチ
The plump whip of love, the whip of love!
お願いなぶってお姉さま
Please tease me, Onee-sama!
キモくてごめんなさい
I'm sorry for being gross!
ありのままで キャストオフ
Just as I am, cast off!
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Inhale, exhale, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
おーねーえーさーまーー！
O-n-e-e-s-a-m-a!
刮目せよ！
Pay close attention!
YMDは古い！
YMD is outdated!
時代はYSOだ！
Now is the era of YSO!
YSOとは何か？
What does YSO stand for?
そう！
Yes!
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！
YAtara Sexy Onee-sama!
YSO!
YY YY
YY YY YSO
YY YY YSO YY YY
YSO YY YY YSO
YY YY YSO
お姉さま！お姉さま！
Onee-sama! Onee-sama!
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！
YAtara Sexy Onee-sama!
ほんわかドジっ子姉御肌
Gentle, clumsy, big-sisterly type...
クーデレ ツンデレ 小悪魔系
Cool-headed, tsundere, little devilish...
いろんなお姉が居るけれど
There are all kinds of Onee-samas, but...
あらあらウフフが優勝です
The "Ara ara, ufufu" one is the absolute best!
もち肌（ぽにぽに）太もも（すりすり）
Smooth skin (squishy), thighs (rub-rub)
ギューして（むにむに）居なけりゃ無理無理ぃ！
Hug me (squeezey), I can't live without you!
あぁん、お姉さまが居ない世界なんて
Ah, a world without Onee-sama...
耐えられないでちゅううう！
I can't bear it, chuuu!
そうして、我が輩は、赤ちゃんになった。
And so, I became a baby.
なでなで、よしよしされる幸せな世界。
A happy world of being patted and coddled.
今日もまた、お姉さまの太ももに顔をうずめ、
Today, again, burying my face in Onee-sama's thighs...
よだれを垂らす。
And drooling.
これが、人生なのだ。
This is what life is.
キモく正しく美しく
Grossly, rightfully, beautifully!
おいでって言ってお姉さま
Tell me to come here, Onee-sama!
抱っこ抱っこしてください
Please hold me, hold me!
本能が剥き出しゾ
My instincts are laid bare!
足のムチムチ 胸のムチ
The plump legs, the whip of the chest!
失礼します お姉さま
Pardon me, Onee-sama!
全裸でごめんなさい
I'm sorry for being naked!
ありのままで キャストオフ
Just as I am, cast off!
愛してますお姉さま♡
I love you, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Inhale, exhale, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！
YAtara Sexy Onee-sama!
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
すーはー すーはー お姉さま♡
Inhale, exhale, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡ あぁ お姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Oh, Onee-sama ♡
おーねーえーさーまーー！
O-n-e-e-s-a-m-a!
ばぶー
Babu...
ふふふ。というわけで
Heheh. And with that,
新曲を披露させていただきました。
I have performed my new song.
タイトルは、お姉様、
The title is... "Onee-sama,
お姉様ラブコールです。
Onee-sama Love Call."
ちゃんとお姉様のあとにハートがつくっていうやつです。
It's the one with a heart right after "Onee-sama."
えー、ビートマリオさんとまのさんに作ってもらいました。
Um, it was made for me by beatMARIO-san and Mano-san.
依頼したときはなんか
When I requested it, they said something like,
「最近のラプラスさんを見てたら、
"Watching the recent Laplus
なんか楽しく作れました」みたいな言ってくれました。
made it really fun to write."
とんでもない曲になっちゃったぜ。
It turned into an unbelievable song!
収録のときも、あ、これはまあ後でリリースされるんですけど、
During the recording—ah, this will be released later,
まあなんかね、収録するときもね、
but anyway, during the recording,
なんか「もっとキモく！もっとうちなるお姉様への想いを込めながら、
they were like, "Be creepier! Sing while putting more of your inner feelings for Onee-sama
歌ってください」とか言われて...
into it!" and stuff...
あんなディレクションは初めてでした。
That was the first time I got that kind of direction.
そんな曲がこのあと、
And that song...
え、MVがね、私のこのチャンネルでプレミア公開されますよー。
the MV will premiere right after this on my channel!
え、そして、まあ今日25日なんですけど、
And, well, today is the 25th,
明日26日に日付変わった瞬間に、この曲がリリースされてしまいます。
but as soon as the date changes to tomorrow the 26th, this song will be released.
さらに何と、ま、これはね、ちょっとサムネにもね、
Furthermore, what's more—well, I wrote "major announcement"
ちょっと釣り、釣りみたいな感じで重大発表みたいな感じで書いたんですけど、
on the thumbnail, kind of like clickbait—
何と、ついに、
but actually, finally,
私ラプラス・ダークネス、一人で初めてのアルバムが発売されるぜ！イェーイ！
my first solo album, Laplus Darknesss, is going to be released! Yay!
いや、なんか一年に一曲しかオリジナル曲ださなかったのに、
I mean, I used to only release one original song a year,
去年狂ったようにオリ曲出して、
but last year I released them like crazy,
今年も出して、
and this year too,
アルバムが出せるようになるなんてね、感慨深いでございます。
so being able to release an album is deeply moving.
そして、なんと今回は2種類出るんだけど、
And we've got two versions coming out this time.
え、一つ目がね、ラプラス・ダークネス 1st Album 「ラプ様アーティスト化計画」
First is Laplus Darknesss 1st Album "Lap-sama Artist-ification Project"...
高いやつ！
the expensive one!
てことで、高いやつです。
So, that's the expensive one.
でもう一つが、ラプ様アーティスト化計画、
And the other is "Lap-sama Artist-ification Project"...
安いやつ！
the cheap one!
ということで、えっと、まあ、
So, um,
お金を、持っている、ね、大きいお友達用のアルバムと、
an album for older friends who have money,
まあお小遣いちょっとママにお願いしようかな、
and one at a price where you could ask your mom,
ママ買って、みたいなののでお願いできそうな値段の、
like, "Mom, please buy it for me,"
まあホロライブで出てるアルバムだと一番安いんじゃない？
which is probably the cheapest album ever released in Hololive...
っていうくらい、安いやつ！の2種類があるよ。
the cheap one! There are two versions.
え、この配信のあとから、ホロライブ公式ショップで予約開始だから、
Pre-orders start on the Hololive official shop right after this stream,
みんな予約してね。
so everyone, go pre-order!
詳しくはホームページをチェック！
Check the homepage for details!
さっき披露した新曲ももちろんアルバムに入るぜ。
Of course, the new song I just performed is also in the album.
さ、新曲オーディションは終わったし、
Well, the new song audition is over.
なんかあとは結果待つだけなんで、おやすみバイバイ。
Now we just have to wait for the results. Goodnight, bye-bye!
おつかれ。
Good work.
優勝したらね、賞品って言ってたんだっけ。なんだろうな。
Wait, did they say there's a prize if I win? I wonder what it is.
プロデューサー：やりましたね！優勝ですよ！
[Producer: You did it! You won!]
ラプラス・ダークネス：流石にレッスンとか急すぎたって～
Laplus Darknesss: For real, those lessons and stuff were way too sudden~
もうへとへと...
I'm completely exhausted...
プロデューサー：…はい、分かりました！　ラプラスさん…
[Producer: ...Yes, I understand! Laplus-san...]
お？
Oh?
プロデューサー：今すぐいきますよ！大型コラボの現場へ！！！
[Producer: We're going right now! To the set of a major collab!!!]
え？何に？え、何に、何に、何に？どこ行くのー？
Eh? For what? Eh, what, what, what? Where are we going?!
みんな、こんばんはー！
Everyone, good evening!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
短い時間だけど、一緒に楽しもうね！
It's a short time, but let's have fun together!
今日は、特別なゲストが来てくれています！
Today, we have a very special guest!
ホロライブの、ラプラス・ダークネスさんです！
From Hololive, it's Laplus Darknesss-san!
え、本当に？
Eh, really?
あ、本当に？ラプ様、降りていらっしゃった...
Ah, really? Lap-sama has descended...
本当にラプ様ですか？
Are you really Lap-sama?
はい！はじめまして！
Yes! Nice to meet you!
あ、はじめまして...
Ah, nice to meet you...
今日はご一緒できて光栄です！
I am honored to perform with you today!
あ、はい...
Ah, yes...
なんて呼んだらいいですか？
What should I call you?
あ、あの、敬語、敬語やめてください、あの...
Ah, please, don't use polite language...
吾輩のことは、あの、ラプくんって呼んでください。
Please call me Lap-kun.
あ！
Ah!
吾輩も、あの、りなみお姉さんって呼んでもいい、いいですか？
Can I also call you Rinami-oneesan?
もちろん！
Of course!
りなみお姉さんって呼んでくれると嬉しいな！
I'd be happy if you call me Rinami-oneesan!
ラプくん！
Lap-kun!
りなみお姉さん...
Rinami-oneesan...
はい！ラプくん！
Yes! Lap-kun!
今日は、私の曲を披露させてもらうんだけど...
Today, I'm going to perform my song...
ラプくんも会場を盛り上げるために...
...and to help hype up the venue, Lap-kun...
ちょっとだけ一緒に参加してくれるんだよね？
...is going to join in a little bit, right?
はい、あの、恐縮です。あの、本当は...
Yes, I'm honored. Actually...
ちょっとこんな近くで見れるだけでも嬉しいんですけど...
...just being able to watch you this close makes me happy, but...
微力ながら、参加させていただきます！
...I'll happily participate to the best of my ability!
うふふ、一緒に共演できて嬉しいよ！
Hehe, I'm so glad we can perform together!
素敵なライブになるといいね！
I hope it will be a wonderful live performance!
はい。
Yes.
それじゃ、早速一曲披露させてもらおうかな！
Well then, I'll go ahead and perform my first song!
ラプくん、準備はいい？
Lap-kun, are you ready?
はい、もちろん、あの、行きます、準備します、あ、行きます！
Yes, of course! I'll get ready, here I go!
みんなも一緒に楽しもうね！
Let's all have fun together!
それでは一曲目、聞いてください！
Now then, please listen to the first song!
愛の 愛の コーダ
Love's, love's coda...
今日は少しだけ
...today, just a little bit...
飛び越えてみちゃう
...shall we jump across?
36℃ U・B・U / 作詞：Soflan Daichi 作曲・編曲：伊藤翼
[Song: 36°C U・B・U / Lyrics: Soflan Daichi, Comp/Arr: Tsubasa Ito]
全然始まらない
Not starting at all...
物語を見ているような気分
...like I'm watching a story that won't begin.
淡々と君にお知らせします
Indifferently, I'll let you know.
このまま行けばエンドロールでU・E
If we go on like this, it'll end in a "U.E." at the end credits.
そう そろそろその手も待って
Yes, it's about time, wait for that hand...
手出せないの？ そつのなさ
You can't make a move? How flawless.
「ねぇねぇ、ちょっとおでこ貸して♪」
"Hey, hey, lend me your forehead for a bit..."
でラブもデコっちゃう？
...and decorate our love too?
急な「ぎゅっ」でキュンもcute
A sudden tight hug, making my heart skip a beat, so cute.
私のcue受け取ってよ
Receive my cue.
予感に身を委ねてみたいの
I want to surrender myself to this premonition.
私からモーションじゃ王道すぎるでしょ？
A motion from me would be way too cliché, right?
36℃ ウブな君にcautious！
36°C, cautious of the innocent you!
もうちょい私にお熱をあげて欲しいのです
I want you to give me a little more of your fever.
君にとって私は一体なんなの？
What on earth am I to you?
はい、ど〜ぞここからは君の番
Yes, go ahead, from here on it's your turn.
上手く言おうなんてしないで
Don't try to say it perfectly.
ちょっと不自然くらいじゃなきゃ
Unless it's a little awkward...
恋なんてそう始まりようがないもの
...there's no way love could ever begin.
かくかくしかじか... つまりはlove song
This and that... in other words, a love song.
出来不出来は置いて溺溺を希望
Put aside the quality, I hope for infatuation.
ちょっとhighな熱いloveにうなされてみたい？
Want to be delirious with a somewhat high, hot love?
キホンノキホン 恋の三大cha cha cha
The absolute basics, love's big three cha-cha-chas:
chance・chase・challenge
Chance, chase, challenge.
用事のないメッセージ さりげないタッチ
A message with no purpose, a casual touch.
翻訳すればすべてが つまりラビュー
If translated, it all means "I love you".
頭で考えずに脊髄反射で応えて
Answer by spinal reflex, without thinking in your head.
no no だけじゃ能がないよ
Just saying "no no" is no good...
そうよあともう一歩
...yes, just one more step.
3・2・1で cha cha cha cha cha
At 3, 2, 1, cha cha cha cha cha!
やればできる子 素直でよろしい
You can't do it if you try, being honest is good.
36℃ ニブい君にcautious！
36°C, cautious of the dense you!
「どうせ・だって・でもでも」なんて
Saying things like, "after all," "because," "but but"...
3Dを抜け出し異次元的ステキをいっぱい感じて
...escape 3D and feel plenty of other-dimensional wonders.
はい、ど〜ぞここからは君の番
Yes, go ahead, from here on it's your turn.
「違うかも…」なんて構わないで
Don't worry about "it might be wrong..."
ちょっとくらいの勘違いがなきゃ
Unless there's a little misunderstanding...
恋なんてそう始まりようがないもの
...there's no way love could ever begin.
ラプくん！お誕生日おめでとう！
Lap-kun! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
一緒に！
Together!
クラップ！
Clap!
はい、はい、はい、はい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
「ねぇねぇ、ちょっとおでこ貸して♪」
"Hey, hey, lend me your forehead for a bit..."
でラブもデコっちゃう？
...and decorate our love too?
急な「ぎゅっ」でキュンもcute
A sudden tight hug, making my heart skip a beat, so cute.
私のcue受け取ってよ
Receive my cue.
予感に身を委ねてみたいの
I want to surrender myself to this premonition.
私からモーションじゃ王道すぎるでしょ？
A motion from me would be way too cliché, right?
36度とウブな君に交渉
Negotiating with naive you at 36 degrees
もうちょい私にお熱は上げてほしいのです
I want you to get a little hotter for me
余裕に見えて私も一杯一杯で
Looking composed, but I'm actually at my limit
ハイ、少々本音を打ち明けちゃう？
Yes, shall I reveal my true feelings a little?
完璧なおねだりだって
Even the perfect begging
ちょっとくらいの隙がなくちゃ
There must be at least a little gap
好きになってって言われるはずないでしょ？
Or there's no way you'll be told "I love you," right?
だから君を
So, as for you...
惹きつけて待っています
I will attract you and wait.
いつだって
Always...
ねえ
Hey...
ちょっとハイなマツエクに
With slightly high-volume lash extensions
連れ去られてみたい
I want to be swept away
36度とU・B・Uでした！
That was "36°C U・B・U"!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
最高でした！
It was awesome!
ラプ君、ありがとう！
Lap-kun, thank you!
一緒にパフォーマンスしてくれて嬉しいよ！
I'm so glad you performed with me!
あ、あの、吾輩、楽しかったです！
A-About that, I had a lot of fun!
あの、間近でりなみさんのパフォーマンス見られて、もう…光栄でした！
Seeing Rinami-san's performance up close, I'm... so honored!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えっと、今日は次の曲が最後になるんだけど…
Um, today's next song will be the last one...
ええ！？
What?!
早すぎます！まだ見たいです！
It's too fast! I want to see more!
もう、名残惜しいけど…
Oh, it's sad to say goodbye, but...
次の曲はみんなにも声を出してほしいな！
I want everyone to cheer along for the next song!
一緒に最後まで楽しもうね！
Let's enjoy it together until the very end!
ラプ君も？
You too, Lap-kun?
もちろんです！もう声枯れるまでやります！
Of course! I'll do it until my voice goes hoarse!
ラプ君、喉は大事にしてね。
Lap-kun, take care of your throat.
あ、あの、りなみお姉さん！吾輩の先輩も、どうしてもライブ見たいって言ってるんですけど、呼んでいいですか？
U-Um, Rinami-oneesan! My senior says she really wants to see the live show too. Can I call her over?
え？誰、誰？ぜひ！
Oh? Who is it? Sure, by all means!
すいません、あ、呼び出ししましょう。
Sorry, ah, let's call her over.
やば…！
Oh my gosh...!
よ、よろしくお願いします！
P-Please treat me well!
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat me well!
さくらみこさん、お会いできて光栄です！
Sakura Miko-san, it's an honor to meet you!
こ、こちらこそです！パフォーマンス楽しみにしてます！
L-Likewise! I'm looking forward to your performance!
うん！お姉さん、頑張っちゃうよ！
Yeah! Big sis is going to do her absolute best!
可愛すぎる…！
Too cute...!
それでは、次の曲…
Well then, the next song...
聴いてください！
Please listen!
回想中 熱くなり お茶いかが？
During recollections, it gets hot. Would you like some tea?
冷静に 大人になって
Calmly, become an adult.
ハートは君にまだ教えずに
Still not telling you about my heart,
ご相談 ちらちらと
consulting you, glancing your way.
余裕身につけて言う「お相手はyou？」
Putting on a calm air, I say, "Are you my partner?"
ドラマのようなことしないで嬢
Don't do something like in a drama, young lady.
噛めば噛むほど美味しいレイディー 例に
The more you chew, the more delicious, like a lady, for example
甘え方を見せてほしい
I want you to show me how you pamper.
一緒に歌ってくれる？
Will you sing along with me?
はみ出したい！
I want to break out!
変われないの 自由形がいい子は好き放題
Can't change, the freestyle good girls do as they please.
その塩梅 もうわからないの
I don't know that balance anymore.
優しいふりしてただ焦らせてる
Pretending to be kind, just making me impatient.
二人ともよくできました！
You two did great!
そっと口角上げ君を 魅せて君を
Gently raising the corners of my mouth to enchant you
そっと心タップ君を あぁ君を
Gently tapping my heart, oh, you...
知りたい
I want to know.
ラストもお願い！
One last time, please!
はみ出したい！
I want to break out!
変われないの 自由形がいい子は好き放題
Can't change, the freestyle good girls do as they please.
その塩梅 もうわからないの
I don't know that balance anymore.
優しいふりしてただ焦らせてもっと
Pretending to be kind, just making me impatient more.
遠慮してん？ はしゃげないの
Are you holding back? Can't make a fuss.
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead you completely well, but...
そのボーダーもう超えらんないの
I can't cross that border anymore.
そもそも話まだ隠して
Still hiding the story in the first place
見つめてる
staring at you.
はぁー！『clumsy trick』でした！
Phew! That was "clumsy trick"!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
最高だった！ / 最高です！
You were awesome! / It was the best!
らぷくんとあんな風に一緒にパフォーマンスすることになるなんて、楽しかったな〜
I never thought I'd get to perform with Lapu-kun like that, it was so much fun!
よかったらこっちで一緒に話そうよ
If you'd like, why don't you come over here and talk with me?
行け行け！
Go, go!
い、いやいや、あの、ここが、ここがやっぱり落ち着くんですけど...
N-No way, I mean, I really feel more at home right here...
さっきは一緒にステージにいてくれたのに...
But you were on stage with me just a moment ago...
行って来いよ、呼ばれてんのだから！
Just go already! You're being invited!
う、今行きます！待っててください！
U-Um, I'm coming! Please wait for me!
がんばれ！
Good luck!
急に出てくるからびっくりしちゃったよ
You popped up so suddenly, you startled me!
も、申し訳ありません、なんか、もう我慢できなくて...
I-I'm so sorry, I just couldn't contain myself anymore...
そんな破天荒なところがらぷくんの魅力だよね。私も見習いたいよ
That wild, unpredictable side is your charm, Lapu-kun. I want to learn from you.
え、いやもう、りりかお姉さんは、もうこのままで素敵です。もうそのままでいてください
N-No, Ririka-oneesan, you are already perfect the way you are. Please stay just as you are.
ありがとう
Thank you.
これからもお互い、アイドルとして頑張ろうね！
Let's both keep doing our best as idols!
あ、もう、恐れ多いです、ありがとうございます。頑張ります
Ah, that is too much honor! Thank you very much! I'll do my best!
またこうやって一緒に共演できたら嬉しいな
I'd be so happy if we could co-star like this again.
あ、それももう、恐縮です！ありがとうございます
Ah, I am extremely humbled! Thank you so much!
今日はありがとう！
Thank you for today!
とっても素敵なミニライブでした！
It was a truly wonderful mini-live!
みんなも楽しんでくれたかな？
I hope everyone enjoyed it too!
それじゃあまたね！
See you next time!
らぷくんも
You too, Lapu-kun!
え？りりかお姉さん？
Huh? Ririka-oneesan?
あ、お姉さん！
Ah, Oneesan!